Guide to the Charles Carsten Platt and Frederick Putnam Platt papers, ca.1937-1955
Platt, Charles Carsten and Frederick Putnam papers, [ca.1937-1955}
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles Carsten Platt and Frederick Putnam Platt papers, [ca.1937-1955]
2852
Charles Carsten Platt, 1880-1967.
12.3 cubic ft.
Includes files, insurance records, paid bills, cancelled checks, blueprints, and drawings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles Carsten Platt (Cornell University Class of 1901) and his brother, Frederick P. Platt, headed F.P. Platt & Brother, an architecture firm. The collection is mostly a file of jobs done by the Platts. Also includes insurance records, paid bills, cancelled checks, and blueprints and drawings.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Charles Carsten Platt (Cornell University Class of 1901) and his brother, Frederick P. Platt, headed F.P. Platt & Brother, an architecture firm which designed the Consolidated Edison Company, Horn and Hardart Automat restaurants, and the New York Athletic Club (of which Charles Platt was a member). Other clients included New York University and Pace College. Charles Platt was a member of the Architectural League of New York and the State Association of Architects; a governor of the Real Estate Board of New York; and a president of the Municipal Art Society in New York City. He served on municipal improvement committees under New York mayors Fiorello H. La Guardia, William O'Dwyer, and Robert F. Wagner, and was a leader in efforts to eliminate slums.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection is mostly a file of jobs done by the Platts. Also includes insurance records, paid bills, cancelled checks, and blueprints and drawings.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Platt, Charles C. (Charles Carsten), 1880-1967.; Platt, Frederick Putnam, d. 1955.; F.P. Platt & Brother.
Subjects:
Architecture--New York (State); Cities and towns--Civic improvement.; City planning.; Slums.; Architects.; City planners.
Places:
New York (N.Y.)--City planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Job file, ca. 1937-1944 (Box 1)
- Job file, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 2)
- Job file, ca. 1944-1947 (Box 3)
- Job file, ca. 1944-1951 (Box 4)
- Job file, ca. 1944-1953 (Box 5)
- Job file, ca. 1945-1949 (Box 6)
- Job file, ca. 1944-1948 (Box 7)
- Job file, ca. 1945-1951 (Box 8)
- Job file, ca. 1951-1953 (Box 8)
- Job file, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 10)
- Job file, ca. 1943-1945 (Box 11)
- Insurance records, paid bills, cancelled checks, ca. 1950-1955 (Box 12)